José Hermilo Ortega Martínez

Software Engineer

Hermilo.jh@gmail.com | (236) 878-1239 | LinkedIn.com/in/HermiloMartinez | HermiloOrtega.com | Vancouver, BC

Summary

Energetic Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience helping companies reduce time, costs, and effort by automating processes through high-performance Software and Web Applications. Implementing advanced methodologies to manage businesses according to their needs. Team player with a will-do attitude and strong motivation to learn new ways to improve every day.

Work Experience

Web Developer / System Administrator

Epic Inspired (Jul 2020 – Present)

- Complete planning, analysis, design, development, QA and launch of computer systems, web applications, system architecture as well as web development, with the use of LAMP Stack and Microsoft Framework.
- Create, implement, and improve methodologies, plans and strategies for increased security and preventing possible breaches in company files, websites, web apps and software's.
- Server-side maintenance and management for on-site and cloud services.
- Secure file management, backup systems, data management and document handling.
- Technical support and troubleshooting as required following company protocols.
- Lead and coordinate teams with different skills and experience to develop websites.

Full Stack Software Developer

Jucod IT Company (Jan 2020 – Present)

 Help companies to reduce time, cost, and effort by automating processes through high-performance web technologies and implementing advanced methodologies to manage business according to their needs using primarily the Microsoft Framework and Technologies as well as the LAMP Stack.

Full Stack Software Developer

10Star (September 2019 – November 2019)

- Improve the management and control of contracts, events, and budgets of the company by developing a high-quality internal web application using a LAMP Stack.
- Complete planning, analysis, design, development, and execution of the web application.
- Conduct analyses and oversee administrative operations related to budgeting, contracting and project planning and management processes.
- Assemble data and prepare periodic and special reports, manuals, and correspondence.

Team Manager

Spanish Bank East Concession (May 2019 – July 2020)

- Improve the operations time with the implementation of new methodologies in the front desk, kitchen, and storage, increasing the productivity of employees and teamwork, reducing time lost and disorganization.
- Attention to customers and suppliers to answer questions and solve any questions or complaints.
- Hiring and training new and existing staff to teach procedures and methodologies.

Senior Software Engineer

Altos Hornos de México (June 2013 – December 2018)

- Reduced the time of operations, enforcement and money lost in different departments of the company by developing more than 10 high-quality and reliable internal software and web applications using Microsoft Frameworks such as C#, ASP, .Net Core, as well as LAMP Stack.
- Improved the performance of 10 additional internal software previously developed by other developers, implementing new methodologies and algorithms which help in the processing of the information.
- Design and programming of gueries in SQL Server using the best practices.
- Complete planning, analysis, design, development, QA and launch of Web and Windows Applications.
- Creation and coordination of reports, policies, formats, system manuals, and meetings.
- End-user support and training to answer questions or solve any issue about systems.

Education

Web and Mobile Application Development	2020
Master's Degree in Software Engineering Instituto de Estudios Universitarios (Puebla, México)	2017
Master's Degree in Leadership and Management Universidad Autónoma del Noreste (Coahuila, México)	2016
Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science	2013
Awards	
Honorable Mention Award	2018
Honorable Mention Award	2017
icenses & Certifications	
Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals	2021
Verified International Academic Qualifications World Education Services (Issued Nov 2020)	2020
Software Testing Fundamentals	2019
Development of Mobile Apps	2015
Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer	2013

Side Projects

CoronaRace

github.com/HermiloOrtega/CoronaRace

- CoronaRace is a single player game where the main objective is to run from your home to the school avoiding all the viruses on the street don't get sick and die on the way.
- The game is built with Java and FXGL Games Library as well as JavaFX.

HermiloOrtega.com

github.com/HermiloOrtega/HermiloOrtega.com

- HermiloOrtega.com is my personal portfolio website where I show more about me, my experience, portfolio, Hobbies, Awards, Etc.
- The Website was built using React and NodeJS.

LinkedIn Apps

github.com/HermiloOrtega/LinkedinApps

• LinkedIn Apps is a repository of practice with all the apps that are presented in the different C# and ASP Paths from LinkedIn Learning. The main intention of this repository on GitHub is to continue practicing new C# Frameworks, Libraries, methodologies, etc. to don't lose any practice in the language.